<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
    <title>HIST5702W</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Example Site Description</description>
    
    <item>
        <title>A Library of Readings</title>
        <link>/library.html</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 13:38:28 EST</pubDate>
        <description>Traditionally, one would sort these to go into the various weeks of the seminar. If you look at the [schedule](weekly.html) you'll see that there is a broad progression through the various stages of doing digital history work - from setting up your research environment, through getting & cleaning your data,...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Schedule, Readings & Tutorials</title>
        <link>/weekly.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 09:13:29 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  Schedule, Readings & Tutorials ![](http://programminghistorian.org/gallery/sustainable-authorship-in-plain-text-using-pandoc-and-markdown.png) [A Library of Readings](library.html)  General pattern Each week, we will begin Monday at 9 to allow for childcare arrangements. You are welcome to arrive at 8.30 as per the official schedule, but I will not begin until 9. Consequently, I will also...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>/getting-started.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 09:12:52 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  Syllabus img src="/uploads/Doc-Brown-Martin-Casanova.jpg" style="PADDING-RIGHT: 5px"align="left"  _Where we're going, we don't need roads_. (Brown, 1985)  Objectives: I've been doing digital archaeology and digital history for over ten years. I still don't know the answer to the questions below, so I look forward to puzzling these out with...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Some Digital History Projects</title>
        <link>/someprojects.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 09:12:50 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  A Small Unrepresentative Sample of Digital History Projects There are **many** different ways of doing digital history. You might find something to inspire you here, to delight you, to confound you. As you explore these, note the date of creation, the platform or tools used, and the design...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>HIST5702W @ Carleton U 2016</title>
        <link>/index.html</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 22:54:54 EST</pubDate>
        <description>Course Site.</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Final Project</title>
        <link>/final-project.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 21:29:48 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  You Can Build a Video Game  Video games are the new lively medium  iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PVbCECjxFds" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen/iframe Before you go any further, I would like you to play some pieces of 'ergodic' literature ('ergodic' in that they take work to 'read'): - Buried, by...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Assessment</title>
        <link>/assessment.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 21:16:16 EST</pubDate>
        <description> Assessment **Active participation** in the class discussion. Leadership and positive contributions to the class discussion, wherever that takes place. The course hashtag is hist5702w. (I am [@electricarchaeo](http://twitter.com/electricarchaeo) on Twitter). Each week will involve one or two students giving us a warts-and-all post-mortem on a programming historian tutorial. You will...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Future Proofing your Research</title>
        <link>/futureproof.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 21:16:14 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  Future Proofing Your Research Back in 2003, Roy Rosenzweig wrote [Scarcity or Abundance? Preserving the Past in a Digital Era](http://chnm.gmu.edu/essays-on-history-new-media/essays/?essayid=6). Roy saw that the seeming abundance of historical materials online was illusory, that without proper training and funding, we would *lose* materials. If anything [things have gotten worse](http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/11/the-irony-of-writing-about-digital-preservation/416184/)....</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>/about.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 21:16:13 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  Shawn Graham Associate Prof of Digital Humanities [@electricarchaeo](http://twitter.com/electricarchaeo) - research blog at [electric archaeology](http://electricarchaeology.ca) - open notebook at [shawngraham.github.io](http://shawngraham.github.io) - office at PA 406 - email at shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca - Office hours by chance or arrangement iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaSblM-Qz3A" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen/iframe ...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Crafting Digital History</title>
        <link>/crafting.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 21:16:13 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  On Craftiness img src="/uploads/inspiration.png" style="PADDING-RIGHT: 5px"align="left"Great art comes from inspiration. Technical skill, yes of course. But 'inspiration' - the divine breath. Science? Science requires hard work and graft. Careful observation, attention to detail, replication, routine and method. Carefully record everything, and someone else could (should be able to)...</description>
    </item>    
    
    <item>
        <title>Open Access</title>
        <link>/openaccess.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 13:44:59 EST</pubDate>
        <description>[TOC]  Open Access Research _Open access is not simply about putting data online._ (A deep discussion about the failings of the techno-utopianism of 'the digital' is [Colleen Morgan](https://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/)'s [phd thesis](https://www.academia.edu/2997156/Emancipatory_Digital_Archaeology)). Open access means making our data available in *useful* formats; it means *exposing our thought process*. It implies transparency...</description>
    </item>    
    
</channel>
</rss>